<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gary A. Newsome]]></title><description><![CDATA[Developer, musician, creative type being.]]></description><link>https://www.garyanewsome.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 03:48:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The Mysterious Disappearance of Joe Johnson]]></title><link>https://www.garyanewsome.com/the-mysterious-disappearance-of-joe-johnson/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.garyanewsome.com/the-mysterious-disappearance-of-joe-johnson/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 16:01:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Made For TV Movies]]></title><description><![CDATA[Track Listing AF Hypnotik Virginia Zombie Aviatrix inkuknow1 Endless Screaming]]></description><link>https://www.garyanewsome.com/made-for-tv-movies/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.garyanewsome.com/made-for-tv-movies/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Track Listing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypnotik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virginia Zombie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aviatrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inkuknow1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Endless Screaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Setting Up Phalcon PHPs Docs]]></title><description><![CDATA[I recently made my first open source contribution to the PhalconPHP docs. It was a small contribution, but nevertheless it felt nice, and it…]]></description><link>https://www.garyanewsome.com/setting-up-phalcon-phps-docs/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.garyanewsome.com/setting-up-phalcon-phps-docs/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 19:29:15 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I recently made my first open source contribution to the PhalconPHP docs. It was a small contribution, but nevertheless it felt nice, and it was a great way to start being an open source contributor. This post is basically just to document my experience setting up the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs-app&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://phalconphp.com/&quot;&gt;PhalconPHP&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;To note, I am using 2015 MacBookPro running macOS Sierra&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started by following the setup guide at &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.phalconphp.com/post/helping-with-documentation&quot;&gt;https://blog.phalconphp.com/post/helping-with-documentation&lt;/a&gt;. Which worked really well and it got me close, but there were a few tweaks I needed to make to get things running on my end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main difference between the conventional setup and the way I did it was, not using Nanobox to serve the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs-app&lt;/code&gt;. I tried a couple of times, but it just wasn’t working out for me. &lt;em&gt;I did use it for the deploy step though.&lt;/em&gt; What I did, with the help of friend, boss, and Phalcon core team member &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PaulSCoder&quot;&gt;Paul Scarrone&lt;/a&gt;, was install &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phalcon/phalcon-devtools&quot;&gt;phalcon-devtools&lt;/a&gt; instead. This allowed me to run the app via a local development server instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, onto the good stuff…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing Phalcon-Devtools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used Composer for the install. &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;composer global require phalcon-devtools&lt;/code&gt; Composer is a dependency manager for PHP, and can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://getcomposer.org/&quot;&gt;https://getcomposer.org/&lt;/a&gt;. This installs phalcon-devtools at &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;~/.composer/vender/bin&lt;/code&gt;. Worth mentioning here, is the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;global&lt;/code&gt; flag. I installed this globally, so I can use it from anywhere on my computer in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, in my &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;.bashrc&lt;/code&gt; file, I created the variable &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;COMPOSERBIN&lt;/code&gt; which I set to the path &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;COMPOSERBIN=&amp;quot;$HOME/.composer/vendor/bin&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you add the variable to your PATH, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;export PATH=$COMPOSERBIN:$PATH&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;.bashrc&lt;/code&gt; was to create the alias, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;alias phalcon=$COMPOSERBIN/phalcon.php&lt;/code&gt;,
this allows you to call the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;phalcon&lt;/code&gt; command from your terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs-app&lt;/code&gt;, the last change I need to make was in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file. I changed the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;APP_URL&lt;/code&gt; line to &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;APP_URL=http://localhost:8000&lt;/code&gt; instead of the default url listed in the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can just &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs-app&lt;/code&gt; folder and type &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;phalcon serve&lt;/code&gt;, then visit &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8000&lt;/code&gt; in your browser of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A list of the available devtools commands can be found in the README.md at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phalcon/phalcon-devtools&quot;&gt;phalcon-devtools&lt;/a&gt; or by typing &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;phalcon --help&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One final note, I actually cloned both the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs-app&lt;/code&gt; repos to my local machine. This allows me to work on the changes in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs-app&lt;/code&gt; repo, then just copy/paste those changes into my &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; repo, where I commit the changes.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Savadoro Beta Available]]></title><description><![CDATA[Cross posted from SavvySoftWorks. SavvySoftWorks, LLC is proud to announce the Savadoro timer. Savadoro is Pomodoro Technique timer, while…]]></description><link>https://www.garyanewsome.com/savadoro-beta-available/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.garyanewsome.com/savadoro-beta-available/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 19:24:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cross posted from &lt;a href=&quot;http://savvysoftworks.com&quot;&gt;SavvySoftWorks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SavvySoftWorks, LLC is proud to announce the Savadoro timer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Savadoro is Pomodoro Technique timer, while this is still in a very early beta stage, we have big ideas for the timer long term. Including integration into Slack as well as the ability to track you and your team’s past progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a little background, per &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; the Pomodoro Technique is a time management technique developed in the late 1980s. Basically, you decide upon a task, then set the timer for 25 minutes. After the timer expires you take a short 3-5 minute break, and then repeat. after 4 times through the cycle you take a longer 15-20 minute break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This technique helps you stay on task as it creates specific periods of focus on a designated task. It also helps you avoid the proverbial “rabbit hole” of getting lost in a specific problem for too long, as the timer will interupt you at the designated time. Giving your brain a break or allowing you a pause to seek help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The timer itself is free for you to try, and is available for download on GitHub. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SavvySoftWorksLLC/savadoro/releases/tag/v0.2.2&quot;&gt;https://github.com/SavvySoftWorksLLC/savadoro/releases/tag/v0.2.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows, Savadoro installs correctly, but does not create a Start Menu item. You can find it via search and create your own desktop shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sorry at this time we only have Mac and Windows versions available. Though Ubuntu will be coming soon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>